Karanjit Singh

thekaranjit@outlook.com | +91 7302117129

Education

Pune University, India

Bachelor of Arts | Oct 2011

CourseWork

UnderGraduate

Computer Applications
Programming
Database Management
English
Accounting
Business Studies

Graduate

English Travel & Tourism Geography

Skills

Microsoft Purview **Azure Information Protection** Sensitivity Labels Exact Data Match **Communication Compliance Azure Administration** Office 365 Exchange administration. Migration SharePoint Administration Teams & One Drive Administration Security and Compliance **Outlook Troubleshooting Multifactor Authentication Email Security Active Directory Powershell Scripting Automation** Sentinel One Proofpoint Cloud Intune, Shareweb Axcient Cloud Backup

Conditional Access Policy

About Me

7+ Years of Experience in Exchange O365 Administration including Extensive exposure in EXO | Windows Server 2019/22 | Active Directory | Exchange hybrid with O365 | ADFS | AAD Connect Installation and Troubleshooting | ITSM tools like SNOW, CW Manage | M365 Security & Compliance | Microsoft 365 Defender | Hybrid Migration | Tenant to Tenant Migration | Azure Identity | SPO | Teams.

Experience

Insight | System Analyst (L2)

January 2023 - Present | Gurgaon, India

- Execute all types of day to day tasks related to O365, AZURE, Intune, Active directory, Migration
- Provide L2 support to L1 engineers and actively work on escalated cases.
- Managed cases related to Exchange Online (O365/AAD Connect/DirSync/ADFS/ConditionalAccess/O365 Security & Compliance/Azure AD/Azure
- Identity.
- Analyse and solve various customer issues and bugs, and act as the liaison between our customers and product teams.
- Root cause analysis on new issues encountered

ConnectWise | Dedicated Tech (L2)

Dec 2020 - January 2023 | Pune, India Dedicated Tech for ICS Data, MI USA

- Execute all types of day to day tasks related to O365, AZURE, Intune, Active directory, Migration
- Perform pre migration and post migration tasks.
- Maintain good customer relation with clients but resolving the issues, deploying new technologies
- Monitor and troubleshoot issues related to AD Servers, Backup management, User management.
- Worked as a M365 SME for the company.
- Maintain updated knowledge of company products and services to better provide customer support and service solutions.
- Created program to get status of backup program and saved manual checking, saved 4+ hours everyday

Language

English (Fluent) Hindi (Native)

Personal Info

Date of Birth:

23/02/1991

Marital Status:

Single

Nationality:

Indian

Contact Information:

thekaranjit@outlook.com +91 7302117129 www.linkedin.com/thekaranjit/

Convergys | L2 Support

Aug 2019 - Dec 2020 | Pune, India Premier Support for Microsoft Office 365

- Handling escalated cases as L2 support
- Troubleshoot Exchange, Azure, Teams and Security & Compliance issues
- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.

Key Achievements

• Solved 99.2% of Level 2 tech support tickets without needing to escalate to Level 3 tech support engineers.

Overseas LLC | Support Associate

Jan 2016 - Apr 2019 | UAE

Biosensors Int | Associate Manager

Mar 2014 - Dec 2015 | India

Disha Online Service | Technical Support

Feb 2011 - Feb 2014 | India

Certifications

- Microsoft 365 Exchange Online Support Associate
- Microsoft 365 Identity Support Associate
- Microsoft 365 Outlook Support Associate
- Microsoft 365 Security and Compliance Support Associate

Awesome things I do

- Upgrade my skills
- I cook awesome Indian food
- I go on hiking (4000 Meter Solo Hiker),
- I do vlogging for fun,
- I love graphics designing and video editing
- Digital Marketing
- Create WordPress templates